pluggedin.co.uk 2006-10-15

# Pluggedin Directory Privacy Policy

**Pluggedin Directory Privacy Policy**

This policy explains what information is gathered from web clients visiting Pluggedin Directory web server, and how that information is used. Information is gathered from clients via several methods that are outlined below. Pluggedin Directory may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

Personal information collected and/or processed by Pluggedin Directory is held in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act 1998.

How we use the information  
The information you supply to us is used in the following ways:  
If you register to receive your email newsletter, we will use your personal information:

  * " To promote and market third party services which may be of interest to you, if you elect to opt-in to receive such marketing. 
  * " You will ALWAYS be given the option to opt-out of any future mailing. Once removed from our mailing list you will not mailed in the future ever again by ourselves or any of our commercial partners

**Log files**

Pluggedin Directory web server tracks requests made of it to centrally held log files. Log files can contain any or all of the following types of data:

  * The date and time of connection
  * Identification of the file(s) requested
  * Whether the request was successful
  * The size (in bytes) sent in response
  * The referring page (where the client came from), as supplied by the client browser
  * The software used to access the server, as supplied by the client browser

Information gathered is used for server system administration, identifying broken links, and for producing usage statistics. Logged information may be kept indefinitely. Log files do not contain any personal information. Examples of data collected automatically from all users include:

  * the Internet protocol (IP) address
  * computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform
  * Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") click stream data, including date and time, and content viewed or searched for on the Site.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small files that are sent from the web server to the client's computer via the client's browser. They are then stored in the client's computer as text files and passed back to the server. Cookies are generally used to identify users and on occasion, prepare customized Web pages for them. Cookies may remain on the client's computer merely for the duration of the session (visit) or they may remain indefinitely. Most standard web browsers may be configured to refuse cookies.

Where Pluggedin Directory uses Cookies they do not contain any personal information and cannot be used to identify an individual user.

**Pluggedin Directory Newsletter**

Pluggedin Directory operates an opt-in newsletter mailing list in order to keep in touch with visitors to the website. The procedure for subscribing to the newsletter requires the user to first submit an email address to be subscribed. Our automated system then sends an email message to the email address supplied informing the owner of that email account of the subscription attempt. We include the IP address from which the subscription attempt originated from in this initial message. At this point the email address supplied is not placed on our mailing list. We also include an "abuse" email address in this email to which the recipient of the message may inform us if they believe their email address has been used without their consent. This initial message also contains a "clickable" hyperlink which the owner of the email account must visit in order to confirm their request to subscribe to the newsletter. This hyperlink is generated automatically and contains information unique to the user. This makes it impossible for anyone other than the recipient of the confirmation email to confirm the subscription. Only once the owner of the email account in question has "clicked" this link is the email address originally submitted added to our mailing list.

Whenever we send out a newsletter mailing it includes at the bottom instructions for the user to follow in order to remove them from our mailing list. Included in the instructions is a hyperlink which the recipient of the newsletter may "click" in order to remove themselves automatically and immediately from the mailing list. The recipient of the newsletter can also reply to the email to request that their email address be removed from our mailing list. Users may also contact Pluggedin Directory via our website via the "Unsubscribe" link to request that their email address be removed.

Again we must stress, all requests for manual removal from our newsletter mailing list are removed as soon as possible and, at the latest, BEFORE the next mailing is sent to the list. Automatic removal via the newsletter hyperlink takes place immediately.

**Links to other websites**

Our website contains links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
